Sergey Kiryushin

Senior Java developer

kiryushin.s.a@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/kiryushinsa/

About Me

Senior Java developer with over 7 years of experience in IT and more than 4 years in finance and banking. Specialize in developing microservice applications based on Java and Spring Framework. Possess solid experience and skills in performance analysis and optimization of business applications. Always seeking ways to improve my work and the work of colleagues.

Work Experience

LLC "Cinimex Data Lab"

Senior Java Developer Java Developer Junior Java Developer $\begin{array}{c} 2024 - Present \\ 2023 - 2024 \\ 2021 - 2023 \end{array}$

Project: BNPL service "Podeli"- financial service for purchases in installments

Technology stack: Spring Framework (Data, Cloud, Security), Hibernate, Java 17/21, Docker, Kubernetes (k8s), RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Yandex Cloud, GitLab, Jmeter, Keycloak, S3, Camunda BPM, Victoria Metrics, Grafana, Jaeger, OpenTelemetry;

- Participated in implementing integration enhancements with major acquiring banks "Tinkoff", "Alfa-Bank",
 "Tvoi platezhi";
- Developed discount functionalities, special offers, and options for various partners based on Camunda BPM;
- Designed and implemented backend automation for partner agreement application processing, including PDF document generation and email notifications;
- Conducted performance research of the application based on: Jmeter tests, metrics, data from async-profiler, heap/thread dump, PostgreSQL statistics, Jaeger;
- Based on the research, proposed and implemented some enhancements that increased performance threefold, through: business logic optimization, changing allocated resource quotas, query optimization, eliminating software bugs;
- Optimization of indexes and SQL queries reducing latency by up to 50%;
- Onboarding of new employees on the project;

Project: "Bank-FSSP"- application for processing electronic requests from "FSSP"in "SMEV" Technology stack: Hibernate, Java EE, Enterprise JavaBeans, IBM MQ, Red Hat JBoss, Oracle Database, Java 8, Jenkins:

- Led and designed project integration with load testing. In 14 days managed to emulate key interaction processes with banking systems (over 20 services), which allowed pre-testing massive performance refactoring before delivery:
- Designed and implemented regular sending of over 10,000 notifications based on events (hold, debit) on client accounts through "sms"and "push"channels;
- Developed and designed enhancements using various banking services: acquiring, currency conversion, holds; in complex financial business logic;

Department of Engineering and Technical Security at RTU MIREA

Technical Specialist 2017 – 2021

• Writing application programs in Java. Database design. Adaptation and implementation of ready-made software solutions. Maintenance and organization of network infrastructure (servers: routing (pfSense), SIP telephony

(Asterisk), video surveillance, NAS, virtualization: Proxmox, monitoring: Zabbix, network equipment: Cisco, OpenWrt).

2017 - 2021

2014 - 2017

Education

Russian Technological University (MIREA) Ryazan State Radio Engineering University

Certificates and Training

- Cisco CCNA Routing and Switching: Introduction to Networks
- Cisco CCNA Routing and Switching: Essentials
- Yandex Cloud Training Certification: "Containerization with Docker "Yandex Managed Service for GitLab "Yandex Managed Service for Kubernetes"
- Internal courses "Cinimex" "Project Management Basics"
 - During 4 months of in-person classes, topics covered included: project and roles within it, project
 management methodologies, project lifecycle, SDLC framework, work estimation, team communication, risk
 assessment, PMI PMBOK 6, JR/Project tools, earned value method, delegation in management, team
 continuity.